<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[yerevancoder]]></title><description><![CDATA[A place for Armenian coders to talk]]></description><link>https://yerevancoder.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 14:00:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The success of JSConf in Armenia and what the future holds]]></title><description><![CDATA[By Edgar Aroutiounian ,
catch me on  twitter Genesis The first conference dedicated just to  JavaScript  in Armenia is
over.  JSConf 201…]]></description><link>https://yerevancoder.com/2017-12-20-init-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://yerevancoder.com/2017-12-20-init-post/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Edgar Aroutiounian&lt;/em&gt;,
catch me on &lt;a href=&apos;https://twitter.com/@edgararout&apos;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Genesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first conference dedicated just to &lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt; in Armenia is
over. &lt;a href=&apos;https://jsconf.am&apos;&gt;JSConf 2017&lt;/a&gt; was an amazing
success and well over 700 people came to &lt;a href=&apos;https://aua.am&apos;&gt;AUA&lt;/a&gt;
to see, learn from and engage with the best programmers
in our Armenian tech community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially had a vision for a conference just for JavaScript in
Armenia, around May 2017 or so. Initial planning was to have the
conference be at &lt;a href=&apos;https://tumo.org/&apos;&gt;Tumo&lt;/a&gt; and I started
that conversation with Tumo officials. However, I started
to get overwhelmed, overworked and couldn’t keep up with all the demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then the most amazing thing happened, the programmer community in
Armenia clearly wanted the conference to still happen and Gevorg
Harutyunyan, my good friend whom I’ve known since basically day one of
starting
&lt;a href=&apos;http://iteratehackerspace.com&apos;&gt;iterate hackerspace&lt;/a&gt; took
the initiative and spearheaded the project. As I watched from San
Francisco, Gevorg assembled a team of very dedicated people from the
Yerevan tech scene and they started implementing JSConf Armenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial estimates of conference attendees began at 100, we thought
that was a huge number at the time…but then it grew to 200
registrants, and then 400, then 800 and eventually to an insane 1500!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of JSConf Armenia shows that there is a huge pent up
demand for community, for knowledge sharing and JavaScript in
Armenia. Many people asked when the next conference was going to be,
even while the current one didn’t even finish yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have many more events planned, the future for tech in Armenia is
very bright and we must continue investing in our greatest resource,
our people.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>